The Muppet Christmas Carol is a music, comedy,
family film directed by Brian Henson.
A retelling of the classic Dickens tale of
Ebenezer Scrooge, miser extraordinaire.
He is held accountable for his dastardly ways during night-time
visitations by the Ghosts of Christmas Past, Present and Future.
Ebenezer Scrooge, played by Michael Caine.
The Great Gonzo as Charles Dickens / Robert Marley / Dr. Bunsen Honeydew /
Betina Cratchit / Rat / Zoot (voice), played by Dave Goelz.
Kermit the Frog as Bob Cratchit / Rizzo the Rat / Beaker / Bean Bunny / Belinda
Cratchit / Beetle / Lips / Pig Gentleman (voice), played by Steve Whitmire.
Tiny Tim Cratchit / Jacob Marley / Ghost of Christmas Present / Lew Zealand / Ma Bear / Mouse / Mr.
Applegate / Penguin / Pig Gentleman / Pops / Rat (voice), played by Jerry Nelson.
Miss Piggy as Emily Cratchit / Fozzie Bear as Fozziewig / Sam the Eagle as Headmaster of Junior High Graduates /
Animal / George the Janitor / Horse and Carriage Driver / Vegetable Salesman (voice), played by Frank Oz.
Rat / Peter Cratchit / Old Joe / Swedish Chef (voice), played by David Rudman.
The Muppet Christmas Carol is a 1992 American Christmas musical film produced
and directed by Brian Henson (in his feature directorial debut).
It is the fourth theatrical film featuring the Muppets.
Adapted from the 1843 novella A Christmas Carol by Charles Dickens with a screenplay written by Jerry Juhl, the film
takes artistic license to suit the aesthetic of the Muppets, but follows Dickens' original story closely.
It is the first Muppet film where a human is the main protagonist.
The film stars Michael Caine as Ebenezer Scrooge alongside Muppet
performers Dave Goelz, Steve Whitmire, Jerry Nelson, and Frank Oz.
It is the first Muppet film to be produced following the deaths of creator Jim
Henson and performer Richard Hunt; the film is dedicated to both.
The film was released in the United States on December 11, 1992, by Buena
Vista Pictures Distribution under its Walt Disney Pictures label.
It was a modest box office success and received generally favorable reviews.
It is the first Muppets film to be produced by Disney, whose parent company would
later acquire the rights to the Muppets characters and assets in 2004.
The film's reputation has grown in the years since its release, and it is
often listed as one of the best Christmas films of all time.
The film explores themes of future, london, england,
based on novel or book, holiday, redemption.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.